大侦探波罗探案集
第2季第6集 双重罪恶
这不是很令人振奋么 波罗?
Isn't it bracing,Poirot?
令人振奋 黑斯廷斯?
Bracing,Hastings?
天气啊
The weather.
不 这天又冷又湿
No,it is cold and wet.
知道么 黑斯廷斯 地球正以
Did you know,Hastings,that the earth is cooling,
每一万两千年降三度的速度在变冷?
at the rate of three degrees every twelve thousand years?
- 不 我不知道 不 - 啊
- No,I didn't know that,no. - Ah.
但喷泉还是很美 不是吗?
Still,beautiful fountain,isn't it?
这喷泉太差劲了 黑斯廷斯
It's feeble,Hastings.
以前的喷泉有活力多了 也更有艺术性
Fountains used to be more vigorous. Artistic too.
我不知道你今天是怎么回事 波罗
I don't know what's wrong with you today,Poirot.
你好像看什么都不顺眼
Nothing seems good enough for you.
我完了 黑斯廷斯
I am finished,Hastings.
- 完了? - 是的
- Finished? - Yes.
我想我该退休了
I shall retire,I think.
但你现在风头正劲 波罗!
But you're at the height of your powers,Poirot!
你真是客气了 黑斯廷斯
You are being kind,Hastings.
不 我没有 你现在很有名气...
No,I 'm not and you've got a nice home...
还有忠实的朋友 辉煌的事业...
Devoted friends,a brilliant career...
不不不 朋友
No,no,no,mon ami.
我什么都不是 我什么都没有
I am nothing. I have nothing.
波罗已经完了
Poirot is finished.
给那家伙一个便士吧 女士?
Penny for the guy,miss?
这才十月的头几天!
It's only the beginning of October !
你不想碰上季节高峰期 不是吗?
You want to avoid the seasonal rush,don't you?
那家伙在哪?
Where's the guy,anyway?
在大门外面 你不信的话可以跟我们过去看看
Out the front. Come and have a look if you don't believe us.
楼下的那个老杂种不让我们和他一起进来
The old basket downstairs won't let us in with the guy.
- 嘿! - 快跑 艾迪!
- Oy ! - Scarper,Eddie !
你们快走! 我要是再看到你们在这...!
You clear off ! If I catch you in here again... !
一没注意他们就溜进来了
As soon as you back's turned...
你让他们损失了一个便士
You did them out of a penny.
噢 这是好事
Oh,a good thing too.
你不会愿意浪费钱鼓励他们的这种行为
You don't want to go wasting your money encouraging them.
我不会的 迪克先生
I shan't,Mr.Dicker.
嗯 我有很多工作要做
Well,I 've got a lot of work to do.
知道么 我不知道他们的父母是怎么想的
You know,I don't know what their parents can be thinking about.
是啊 确实不知道
No,indeed.
嗯 我要开始工作了 迪克先生
Well,duty calls,Mr.Dicker.
好的 如果你遇到任何麻烦 可以来找我
Yes,well. If you ha ve any trouble,you just come to me.
我很担心波罗 莱蒙小姐
I 'm worried about Poirot,Miss Lemon.
他说要退休
He's talking about retirement.
那是因为他五分钟没遇到有趣的案子
That's because he hasn't had an interesting case for five minutes.
我进来之前肯定是拿了钥匙的
I must have had my keys to let myself in.
就这么简单么?
Is that all it is?
就是这个 再就是有人说他是中年人
That and the fact someone said he was middle aged.
问题是 迪克先生一直在说话
The trouble is,Mr.Dicker kept talking.
嗯 他一直就是中年人的形象
Well,he's always been middle aged.
你看过他受洗的照片吗?
Have you seen that photograph of him at his christening?
我知道
I know.
他看起来像是要在董事会上演讲似的
He looks as though he's about to address a board meeting.
谁看起来像是要在董事会上演讲?
Who looks as if he is about to address a board meeting?
噢...呃...是我认识的一个人
Oh...er...This fellow I know.
很有趣的家伙 嗯 不有趣 其实很严肃
Funny chap. Well,not funny. Quite serious really.
- 是公司的董事长... - 黑斯廷斯
- Company director... - Hastings.
- 其实... - 黑斯廷斯
- As a matter of fact... - Hastings.
好吧
Right.
我打算带你去海边 黑斯廷斯
I am going to take you to the seaside,Hastings.
你的灰色小细胞累坏了
Your little grey cells are exhausted.
你需要全面大检修
You are in need of the complete overhaul.
莱蒙小姐
Miss Lemon,
请把我的草药茶给我
my tisane,if you please.
谢谢
Merci.
嗯 这太好了 波罗 我看不出有什么联系?
Well,this is very nice,Poirot. I wonder where the links are?
不不不不 黑斯廷斯 你的游戏玩得还不行
No,no,no,no,Hastings. You are not yet well enough for games.
等你准备好了我会告诉你的
I shall tell you when you are.
真奇怪 这家酒店在北方
Strange that it's called ''The Midland Hotel'',
却叫做"中部酒店" 波罗
when it's in the north,Poirot.
惠特科姆是养身体的好地方
Whitcomb is the place for health.
艾瑞克 我又找到了一些贝壳
Eric,I 've got some more shells.
我希望你感觉好些了 黑斯廷斯
I do hope you are feeling better,Hastings.
嗯 我们才来了半个小时
Well,we've only been here half an hour.
啊 是的 但这里的空气清新是有名的
Ah yes,but the air here is renowned.
看看那些马
Look at the horses.
身上有着最光亮的毛发
Coats of the highest gloss.
让我想到切尔滕纳姆金杯赛上的一匹马
Reminds me of a horse I backed in the Cheltenham Gold Cup.
一点差五分出发的 两点一刻就到了终点
Started at five to one,came in at quarter past two.
噢 这并不很棒啊?
Oh,that is not very good,surely?
不不 这是个笑话 波罗
No. No,it's a joke,Poirot.
很好! 黑斯廷斯 看到了吗?
Good ! Hastings. You see?
你都已经开始讲笑话了
Already you begin to make the jokes.
找个时间你一定要给我解释一下这个笑话
Sometime you must explain to me this joke.
嘿! 看那个 "我最成功的案子"
I say ! Look at that,''My Greatest Cases.
苏格兰警察厅著名的贾普总探长...
A lecture by the renowned Chief Inspector James Japp
的演讲
of Scotland Yard''.
我们不感兴趣 黑斯廷斯
We are not interested,Hastings.
我们还有其它鱼要抓
We have other fowl to fry.
不不不 我很想听
No,no,no. I 'd like to hear that.
- 入场票一个先令 - 噢 天呐
-''Admission one shilling.'' - Oh,mon Dieu,
听贾普总探长演讲 这个价格也太高了
that is a lot of money to hear the Chief Inspector Japp.
妇女组织 桑德林汉姆街 周四八点半
''Women's Institute,Sandringham Street. Thursday 8: 30''.
想象一下贾普站在那里!
Fancy old Japp being up here !
- 给你 女士 - 这很合理
- There you are,madam. - That's very reasonable.
温德米尔的票只要一先令六便士
Windermere for one and six.
如果真要去温德米尔才合理
Reasonable if one wants to go to Windermere.
请给我一张温德米尔的票
Ticket to Windermere,please.
那里很漂亮
It's very pretty there.
我们为什么不试试呢?
Why don't we give it a go?
我听说那里有家很好的酒店提供住宿和早餐
I 've heard there's a pleasant hotel does bed and breakfast.
火车什么时候出发?
At what time does the train leave?
嗯 我认为那不是火车
Well,I don't think it's a train.
巴士吗 黑斯廷斯?
A bus,Hastings?
不不不不 波罗从不坐巴士旅游
No,no,no,no,Poirot does not travel on busses.
噢 别这样 波罗 会很好玩的
Oh,come on,Poirot,it'll be fun.
嘿! 真是个粗鲁的人
I say ! What a rude fellow.
他让我很感兴趣
He rather interested me.
如果不礼貌让你感兴趣的话
Well,if sheer bad manners interests you.
他让我感兴趣是因为他留了胡子
He interested me because he was growing a moustache
目前为止 结果很糟糕
and as yet the result is poor.
你注意到的事真是非同一般 波罗
You do notice the most extraordinary things,Poirot.
但是留胡子是一门艺术 黑斯廷斯
But the growing of the moustache is an art,Hastings.
我同情所有有这种想法的人
I have sympathy with all who attempt it.
我们能得到这些真是太走运了
We were very lucky to get these,you know.
你看
There.
噢!
Oh!
十二个拿破仑的司令官的袖珍画像
Twelve miniatures of Napoleon's Marshals
珍・巴普蒂斯特・雅克・奥古斯丁制作的
by Jean Baptiste Jacques Augustin.
它们真漂亮!
They're beautiful !
每一个的背后都有一撮人物的头发
Each one has a lock of the subject's hair on the back
名字就刻在象牙上
and his name written on the ivory.
这不是很奇怪吗?
Isn't that strange?
你确定你知道要做什么?
Now,you're certain you know what to do?
我当然知道 没事的
Of course I am. It'll be all right.
我会一直把盒子锁在行李箱里 没人会看见的
The box will be locked in my suitcase all the way. Nobody will even see it.
当然 直到合适的时间
Until the appropriate time of course.
当然
Of course.
你没必要担心 知道么
You don't need to worry,you know.
我知道 亲爱的
I know,my dear.
但这是你第一次大任务
But this is your first big commission.
在塞夫勒做端茶服务生也是大任务
That sevres tea-service was quite big.
有很多事情 我...
There was a lot of it. I...
我很担心你没法带它们出行
I was quite worried that you wouldn't have been able to carry it all.
我这几天一定要小心
And I have got to be so careful these days.
我已经打包好了
Well,I 'm all packed.
我应该把盒子放进行李箱吗?
Shall I put the box in my suitcase?
噢 不不不 明早再放吧
Oh no,no,no,lea ve it here till the morning.
你的汽车什么时候出发?
And what time does your coach leave?
九点半
Half past nine.
别担心!
Don't worry !
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
- 请给我一份电报 - 好的 先生
- Telegraph,please. - Certainly,sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
这里是接待处
Reception.
贾普!
Japp !
啊 你好 黑斯廷斯 真是个令人高兴的惊喜
Ah,hello,Captain Hastings. This is a pleasant surprise.
我听说你明天要在这里演讲
I see you're giving a lecture here tomorrow.
嗯 今晚也是 在弗利特伍德
Mm. Tonight,too. In Fleetwood.
周五 巴洛造船厂 为了慈善基金 你知道的
Friday,Barrow in Furness. For the Benevolent Fund,you know.
早上好 黑斯廷斯
Good morning,Hastings.
嗯 嗯
Well,well.
为北方的气候做准备 嗯 波罗?
Prepared for the Northern climate,eh,Poirot?
早上好 总探长
Good morning,Chief Inspector.
黑斯廷斯 汽车五分钟后就要出发了
Hastings,the coach lea ves in five minutes.
他怎么了?
What's got into him?
我十二点四十到莱德伯恩
I 'll be at Redburn at twelve forty.
我不想在那里到处闲晃
I don't want to have to hang about there.
不 我知道
No,I know.
我知道你的工作更困难了
I know you've got the more difficult job.
我们会成功的 别担心
We'll make it,don't worry.
我会在我们计划好的地方等你
I 'll wait for you where we arranged.
只要没有任何麻烦
Just so long as there isn't any fuss.
不 听着 我现在必须走了
No. Look,I 've got to go now
不然就赶不上巴士了
or I 'll miss the bus.
是的 你也是
Yes. You,too.
还要什么其它的吗 女士?
Anything else,ma'am?
你为什么对贾普那么粗鲁 波罗?
Why were you so beastly to Japp,Poirot?
粗鲁 黑斯廷斯?
Beastly,Hastings?
不是因为他要做演讲吧?
It's not these lectures he's giving,is it?
演讲?
Lectures?
我们的行李要放在哪里?
Where can we put our luggage,please?
行李放在后面
The luggage round the back.
噢...
Oh...
噢 再次抱歉
Oh. Sorry again.
你是瞎了还是怎么了?
You blind or something?
真是个粗鲁的人!
What a rude man !
你好 小姐
Bon jour,mademoiselle.
噢 你好
Oh. Bon jour.
早上好 我来吧
Morning. May I?
啊 谢谢
Ah. Thank you.
没关系 反正也不重
That's all right,it wasn't heavy.
现在都上车! 都上车!
All aboard now ! All aboard !
这么说你为你姑妈工作 杜兰特小姐?
So you work for your aunt,Miss Durrant?
是的 我们专门从事高品质的古玩
Yes,we specialise in beautiful quality antiques.
当然 我还在学怎么做这门生意
Of course,I 'm still only learning the business.
我敢肯定你会很成功的
I 'm sure mademoiselle will be very successful.
它们中有一些真的很值钱
Some of them are worth an awful lot of money.
我感到很吃惊
I was surprised.
我姑妈在全世界都有客户
My aunt's got clients all over the world.
啊 这么说她经常旅行 嗯?
Ah,so she travels a great deal,eh?
噢 不 完全没有
Oh no,not at all.
如果有人想要某个特定时期的桌子或椅子
If someone wants a particular period table or chair
或者是某个瓷器
or a certain piece of china,
他们给她写信 她就帮他们弄到手
they write to her,and she gets it for them.
这次也是这样
That's what's happened in this case.
你什么意思?
How do you mean?
我姑妈帮一个美国收藏家
Well my aunt got a very valuable set of miniatures
得到了一组很值钱的袖珍画像
for an American collector.
他是坐车过来买的
He's over here on a buying trip.
他住在温德米尔的一家酒店
He's staying in a hotel in Windermere.
如果他喜欢的话 他就会买?
And if he likes them he'll buy them?
我希望如此
I hope so.
我在回程的路上必须很小心
I 'll have to be ever so careful on the return journey.
我的包里到时会有一千五百英镑的...
I 'll ha ve fifteen hundred pounds in my bag...
现金!
in cash!
抱歉 谢谢 对不起
Excuse me. Thank you. Sorry.
嘿!
Whew!
他们这没有草药茶吗 黑斯廷斯?
They ha ve no tisane,Hastings?
不不 通常是有的 但是...
No. No. They usually do,but...
你根本没问 是吗 黑斯廷斯?
You did not ask,Hastings,did you?
我问不出口 波罗
Well,I couldn't,Poirot.
你从来不会帮我问问有没有草药茶
Never will he ask for the tisane for me.
我不知道草药茶是什么东西
I don't know what a tisane is.
噢 那是一种很恐怖的药茶
Oh,it's a sort of horrible herb tea.
那里真是一团乱 他们这只有一个服务生
There's such a scrum out there. They've only got one chap serving.
失陪了
Excuse me.
这个小姑娘急着去哪里?
Where has she hurried off to,the little one?
噢 大概是女人的事吧
Oh,some women's thing,I expect.
啊
Ah.
很不错的女孩 不是吗?
Grand girl,isn't she?
是的 她很好 黑斯廷斯
Yes,she is very nice,Hastings.
你注意到她的眼睛了吗? 很不寻常的颜色
Have you noticed her eyes? Very unusual colour.
噢 相当不寻常 黑斯廷斯
Oh,most unusual,Hastings.
我想那应该叫做蓝色吧
It is called blue,I think.
黑斯廷斯
Hastings,
为什么那些人一直看着我
why do those people keep staring at me
推对方一下就开始笑?
and push each other and laugh?
我想他们以前没见过像你这样的人 波罗
I don't think they've ever seen anyone quite like you before,Poirot.
啊!
Ah!
杜兰特小姐去哪了? 希望她没有错过车
Where's Miss Durrant? Hope she doesn't miss the coach.
她确实很傻 但也许没那么傻
Well she is silly,but perhaps not that silly.
傻?
Silly?
嗯 告诉两个完全陌生的人
Well,to tell two perfect strangers
她的包里即将会有一千五百英镑
that she will shortly be carrying fifteen hundred pounds in her bag
算不上是聪明 朋友
is not the height of sagacity,mon ami.
很抱歉 我那样跑掉了
I 'm so sorry,rushing off like that.
我很担心袖珍画像
I was worried about the miniatures.
我好像看到一个男人从车上拿走了我的行李箱
I thought I saw a man taking my suitcase out of the coach.
我急忙追过去了 结果那箱子是他的
I went flying after him,and it turned out to be his own.
我觉得自己真是个傻瓜
I felt such a fool.
这么说你的箱子没事?
So your case is all right?
噢 是的 还在后备箱里
Oh,yes. It's still in the boot.
但他的箱子和我的箱子一模一样
His was exactly like mine,though.
是哪个男人 小姐?
What man was it,mademoiselle?
就是那个很粗鲁的男人
It was that man who was so rude.
就是那个留着胡子的人
You know,the one with the sort of moustache.
这真是太奇怪了
That is quite curious.
他为什么要拿走他的箱子?
Why did he want his suitcase?
他就住在莱德伯恩这里
He's staying here in Redburn.
越来越奇怪了
More curious and more curious.
他愿意付去温德米尔的全程车票
He was happy to pay the full fare to Windermere.
他把票拿出来的时候我正好看到了
I happened to see his ticket when he presented it.
波罗很喜欢谜团 即使压根没有任何谜团
Poirot loves a mystery,even when there isn't one.
这曾经是我的职业 黑斯廷斯
It used to be my profession,Hastings.
也许你听说过我 小姐?
You have heard of me perhaps,mademoiselle?
你不会是那个魔术师吧?
You're not that conjurer,are you?
也许我是
Perhaps I am.
不 我在莱德伯恩
No,I 'm at Redburn.
不不 我这边一切都是按计划进行
No,no. It's all going according to plan at my end.
没遇上任何麻烦
No trouble at all.
老天啊 你就尽快吧
Well,just as soon as you can,for God's sake.
我们越早离开越好
The sooner we're out of the area the better.
不! 这个...这个没关系
No! It's,it's all right.
- 我来拿吧 - 好吧
- I 'll take that. - All right.
不不 就是有个人要拿我的箱子
No,no,just someone wanted to take my case.
是的! 别太久
Yes! Don't be long.
黑斯廷斯上校1
Captain Hastings!
黑斯廷斯上校!
噢 很抱歉 发生了很可怕的事!
Oh,I 'm sorry,the most awful thing's happened!
怎么了?
What?
它们不见了!
They've gone !
袖珍画像?
The miniatures?
你过来看吧!
Come and look !
我打开了我的行李箱
I opened my suitcase.
袖珍画像就在这里面的公文包里 看
The miniatures were in this dispatch case inside. Look.
锁被撬开了
The lock's just smashed.
你打开的时候就是这样吗?
Was it like this when you opened it?
是的!
Yes!
我不知道该怎么办了!
I don't know what to do!
波罗!
Poirot !
别担心 杜兰特小姐 你待在这里别动
Don't worry,Miss Durrant,you stay here.
我们会解决的
We'll sort things out.
我们要怎么做?
What are we going to do?
朋友
Mon ami.
我是赫尔克里・波罗 一个退休的侦探
I am Hercule Poirot,detective,retired.
我恐怕帮不了你
I cannot help you,I 'm afraid.
我不得不整晚待在这里了!
I 've had to stay here all night!
噢 我到处都找过了
Oh,I 've looked everywhere.
你没有备用钥匙吗?
You haven't got spare keys?
当然没有
Of course I ha ven't.
我还以为你有总钥匙呢
I thought you might ha ve a pass key.
噢 不 我没有 会被指控的 不是吗?
Oh,no. Not me. You'd get accusations,wouldn't you?
怀疑
Suspicions.
你不得不换锁了
You'll have to change the locks.
我不能!
Well,I can't !
如果波罗先生发现我丢了钥匙
Mr.Poirot would never forgive me
他永远不会原谅我的
if he found out I 'd lost the keys.
我不能再在这里待一个晚上了
I can't stay here another night.
嗯
Hmm.
你说这些袖珍画像...
Now these miniature pictures are worth like
价值一千五百英镑?
one thousand five hundred pounds,you say?
是的 起码值这么多
Yes. At least.
我们在这浪费时间 小偷就要逃走了!
The thief's getting away while we waste time !
他跑不远的 小姐 别担心
He won't get far,miss,don't you fret.
这项工作要的是大脑和心计 不是蛮速度
It's brains and cunning as counts in this job,not brute speed.
我和伍德先生谈过了 就是那个美国人
I 've just spoken to Mr.Wood,the American.
一个女人两小时前拜访过他
A woman called on him two hours ago,I 'm a fraid.
伍德先生对袖珍画像很满意
Mr.Wood was delighted with the miniatures
已经把钱付给她了
and paid her for them.
但那是我们到这之前
But that's before we arrived here.
从莱德伯恩出发的快车能比我们早到很多
Well,a fast car from Redburn would have got here long before us.
噢 这都是我的错
Oh,it's all my fault.
听着 杜兰特小姐 你可以把这件事交给我
Look,Miss Durrant. You can lea ve this with me.
你回去惠特科姆 把事情向你姑妈解释一遍
You get on back to Whitcomb and explain things to your aunt.
好吧
Right.
弗拉格警官和我会去见一下贝克・伍德先生
And P.C.Flagg and I will go and interview Mr.J.Baker Wood.
我必须先和警官说一下 先生
I 'll ha ve to talk to the Sergeant first,sir.
注意时间 先生们 快点 喝吧
Time,gentlemen. Come on,drink up.
你看起来真不错!
You look terrific !
你这身装扮我差点没认出来!
I scarcely recognised you in that get up !
就是这么打算的 以免他们听到了我们的风声
That's the idea. Just in case they've got wind of us.
见到你真是太好了
It's wonderful to see you.
我还以为我们没法成功
I thought we'd never make it.
你离开的时候遇到麻烦了吗?
Did you have any trouble getting a way?
正巧什么都没有
None at all,as it happens.
只是走出门
Just walked out the door,
把箱子放上车 然后就开车离开了
put the case in the car and drove off.
我当时都发抖了
I was shaking.
我做好了随时听到大喊的准备
I expected to hear a shout at any moment.
我们做到了!
We've done it !
到目前为止
So far.
你是世上最聪明的女孩
You're the cleverest girl in the world,
也是最漂亮的
as well as the most beautiful.
那个女孩要被她姑妈骂了
She's going to cop it from her auntie,that girl.
她听上去挺聪明的!
Sounds a bright one,she does!
把那些东西留在车上 她自己就下车吃饭了
Leaving all that stuff on the bus while she goes off and has her dinner.
其实是在汽车的后备箱里
Well,it was in the boot of the coach actually.
这个案子有一两个有趣的地方 知道么
There are one or two interesting points about this case,you know.
噢 是吗?
Oh,yes?
比如 为什么公文包被强行打开了?
Well,why was the dispatch case forced open,for instance?
嗯 为了把袖珍画像拿出来
Well,to get these here little pictures out.
但是为什么呢?
But why?
打开杜兰特小姐的箱子
Surely it would have been simpler to open Miss Durrant's suitcase,
把上锁的公文包转移到他自己的箱子里
transfer the dispatch case unopened to his own suitcase
然后离开 不是比浪费时间开锁简单得多吗?
and get away,rather than waste time forcing the lock?
她一把箱子从后备箱拿出来
Well she'd have noticed the difference in weight as soon as she
就能察觉重量不一样 不是吗?
took the suitcase out of the boot,wouldn't she?
那样他逃跑的时间就少了
And he'd have had less time to make his escape.
噢 嗯
Oh. Well,
是啊 有道理
yes. There is that.
我当然什么都没怀疑!
Of course,I didn't suspect anything !
我为什么要呢?
Why should I?
她说她是伊丽莎白・佩恩派来的
She said she came from Elizabeth Penn.
她有袖珍画像
She had the miniatures.
我们能看一下袖珍画像吗 伍德先生?
May we see the miniatures,please,Mr.Wood?
可以
I guess so.
我们还需要对这个女人的描述 先生
We'll need a description of this woman,too,sir.
描述?
Description?
她年轻吗? 漂亮吗?
Was she young? Pretty?
不 先生
No,sir.
她绝对说不上年轻
She most certainly was not young.
或者是漂亮
Or pretty.
她很高 上了年纪 头发是灰白的
She was tall and elderly,grey hair.
她的脸上有斑 还有胡子
She had a blotchy complexion and a budding moustache.
美女? 绝对不是!
A siren? Not on your life !
她是怎么到酒店来的 伍德先生?
How did she arrive at the hotel,Mr.Wood?
坐的酒店的渡轮
On a hotel ferry.
看吧!
There !
是啊 我看到了
Yes. I see.
很漂亮
Very nice.
是啊 为了这十二个东西花了我七千美元
Yeah,at seven thousand dollars,for twelve of those beauties,
我告诉你 这还是还了价的
I 'll tell you,that's some bargain.
我来拿吧 先生
I 'll be taking that,sir.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
这是犯罪的证据 先生
Evidence of a crime,sir.
嘿 你是开玩笑的吧
Well hey,you've got to be kidding.
我们会给你开收据的 登齐尔
You'll get a receipt. Denzil.
我们必须确认谁才是合法得主
We have to assure ourselves who the rightful owner is.
你什么意思 合法得主? 我就是合法得主
What do you mean,rightful owner? I 'm the rightful owner.
我是花了七千美元的合法得主
I 'm seven thousand dollars worth the rightful owner.
这不是我说了算的 先生
That's not for me to say,sir.
那你就别说了! 我来帮你说
Then don't say it! I 'll say it for you,
那些他妈的是我的袖珍画像
those are my goddam miniatures.
这要留给法庭决定 先生
That's for the court to decide,sir.
你是说必须坐船从这个火车站出来?
You mean,you have to come from the railway station by boat?
车站在湖的另一边 那里
The station's on the other side of the lake,there.
噢 我知道了
Oh,I see.
- 日安 - 早上好
- Good day. - Good morning.
阿克赖特先生?
Mr.Arkwright?
是啊 先生
Aye,sir.
你今天有没有载一位年老的女士去湖边酒店?
Did you bring an elderly lady to the Lake Hotel today?
我载了很多女士 先生
I bring lots of old ladies,sir.
很高 头发灰白 有一点胡子...
Tall,grey haired,bit of a moustache...
噢 是啊 我一点十二分在车站载的她
Oh,aye,I picked her up at the station at twelve minutes past one.
你怎么这么确定时间?
How are you so sure of the time?
因为兰开斯特的火车一点钟进站
Because the Lancaster train gets in at one o'clock
十分钟后到达
and it arrived at ten past.
那辆车在莱德伯恩停吗?
Does that train stop at Redburn?
莱德伯恩? 不停!
Redburn? No!
那是马特布鲁克路线 在莱德伯恩停!
That's on the Maltbrook line. Stop at Redburn !
玛丽・杜兰特大约十二点十分到的莱德伯恩
Mary Durrant arrived at Redburn at about ten past twelve.
我是说 这一点我们知道 我们和她在一起
I mean,we know that,we were with her.
一小时后 一位年老的女士在温德米尔这里
An hour later an old lady is here in Windermere
拿着袖珍画像 正在去伍德的酒店的路上
with the miniatures and on her way to Wood's hotel.
现在我肯定是那个留着胡子的家伙乔装的
Now,I 'm sure it was the fellow with the bit of a moustache,dressed up.
他可以坐快车一小时内从莱德伯恩到温德米尔
He could have got from Redburn to Windermere in an hour in a fast car.
但那位年老女士不是坐车到的
But the old lady didn't arrive by car.
她是从火车上下来的!
She got off a train !
那辆火车根本就不去莱德伯恩!
And a train that doesn't go near Redburn at that!
黑斯廷斯
Hastings,
你为什么不留胡子?
why do you not grow the moustache?
什么?
What?
在我留胡子之前 我都没法真的获得面部匀称
I did not achieve true facial symmetry until I grew the moustache.
这让我在年轻的时候很不开心
It caused me great unhappiness as a young man.
我不想要面部匀称! 我要的是帮助
I don't want facial symmetry ! I want help.
啊 我已经退休了 黑斯廷斯
Ah well,I am retired,Hastings.
这样的谜团已经不能让我感兴趣了
Such puzzles no longer interest me.
噢 这真是...
Oh,that's...
我想我早上要回惠特科姆一趟
I think I will go back to Whitcomb in the morning.
噢 好吧
Oh,all right.
- 黑斯廷斯? - 嗯?
- Hastings? - Mmm?
船夫在火车站载她上船
The fact that the Ferryman picked her up at the station
不代表她刚下火车
does not necessarily mean that she got off a train.
但如果她不是坐火车来的 那她是怎么来的?
But if she didn't come by train,how did she come?
谁知道呢? 黑斯廷斯 你已经做得很好了
Who knows? Hastings,you have done well,
但我想你还要在这个案子上花很长时间
but you will be on this case a long time I think.
难道我不知道吗?
Don't I know it!
好吧
Right.
我早上会回莱德伯恩一趟
I 'm going back to Redburn in the morning.
重新构建作案过程 就是这样
Reconstruct the crime,that's the thing.
从头开始
Start from the beginning.
新生的开始
The start of a new life.
我觉得现在不会有什么问题了
I don't think much can go wrong now.
我在车里等你
I 'll wait for you in the car.
你在这啊 先生 这是您的找零
There you are,sir,there's your change.
谢谢
Thanks.
你会回来看我们的 是吗?
Come back and see us again,won't you?
就我所见 是从这里开始的
So,as I see it,it started here.
这个留着胡子的家伙
This fellow with a bit of a moustache
有一个开快车的同伙 载他去温德米尔
had an accomplice with a fast car who drove him to Windermere
而他就在车后座乔装成女人
while he got dressed up as a woman in the back seat.
如果要在这段时间跑完这段路
Need to be a pretty sporty car
必须是一辆很快的车
to do that journey in the time.
什么 你是说像这样的车吗?
What,something like that,you mean?
就是他! 停下!
It's him! Stop !
别停!
Don't stop !
嘿! 这辆车不是用来追踪的!
Here ! That's not meant for chasing !
上车
Get in.
这是巡逻车 不是追踪的车
This is a patrol car,not a chase car.
上车
Get in.
快点 快点 别挡路
Come on,come on. Get out of the way.
让开
Move over.
快点 别挡路
Go on,get out of the way.
我会抓到你的 我会抓到你的
I 'll have you. I 'll have you.
有一段路他们没法转弯了
There's nowhere they can turn off for a bit,
直到他们到了贝克斯戴尔
not till they get to Beckersdale.
他们转弯了
They have turned.
嗯 老天保佑啊!
Well,I 'm blessed !
很快就能抓到他们了 那是条死胡同
Won't get 'em very far. It's a dead end,that is.
只通往海明斯科特 不是吗?
Only goes to Hemmingscote,doesn't it?
希望我们不会遇到对面开来的车
Hope we don't meet anyone coming the other way.
我的天呐!
My God !
- 快点 - 快点 警官
- Come on. - Come on Sarge.
好了 过来 小姐
Right. Come along,madam.
过来 小伙子 出来
Come along,lad. Out you come.
你就不能放过我们吗?
Why can't you leave me alone !
你不知道爱上一个男人是怎么样的吗?
Don't you know what it's like to love a man?
嗯 呃...不
Well,er... no.
不太知道
Not exactly.
警官
Sergeant.
快点 别惹麻烦
Come along. No trouble.
噢 又是你 不是吗?
Oh,it's you again,is it?
我就知道
I might ha ve known.
快点吧 先生
Come along,sir.
我为什么要帮你?
Why should I help you?
因为这样的话我们能把你的钱拿回来
Because that way we might get your money back.
噢 我当然能把钱拿回来
Oh,I 'll get my money back all right.
我的律师已经在从伦敦过来的路上了
My attorney's on his way up here from London.
- 听着 如果我们可以... - 好了
- Look,if we could just...? - All right.
我们可以开始了吗?
Can we just get on with it?
进来吧!
Ready !
嗯?
Well?
不是
No.
好吧
Right.
进来!
Ready !
把帽子拿下来
Take your hat off.
嗯?
Well?
不是
No.
别急 好好看看
Don't hurry. I mean,take a good look.
想象一下他乔装成女人的样子
I mean,imagine him dressed up as a woman.
帽子 裙子 那一类的东西
Hat,skirt,all that sort of thing.
不是他
It's not him.
但他有胡子 你说她有胡子
But he's got a moustache. You said she had a moustache.
给我看袖珍画像的人不是这样的
The woman who sold me the miniatures was nothing like that.
她没有那样的痣
She didn't ha ve a mole like that.
什么样的?
Like what?
天呐 他额头的痣!
Well,that mole on his forehead for God's sake !
这是藏不住的!
Couldn't hide that !
噢
Oh.
等一下
Wait a minute.
等一下!
Wait a minute !
噢 不!
Oh,no!
这是阿曼达・曼德利小姐!
That's Lady Amanda Manderly !
谁?
Who?
你们不看报纸的吗?
Well,don't you guys read the papers?
她和那个小说家私奔了 嗯...
I mean,she's eloping with that novelist,um...
诺顿・凯恩!
Norton Kane !
你是诺顿・凯恩吗?
Are you Norton Kane?
你能跟我一起来真是太好了 波罗先生
It's so good of you to come with me,Mr.Poirot.
不不不 一点也不 亲爱的
No,no,no,not at all,my dear.
我怎么能让这么一位迷人的年轻小姐
How could I possibly lea ve such a charming young lady
陷入这么大的不幸呢?
in so great distress?
但既然我现在在这里
But perhaps now that I am here,
我可以帮你向你姑妈解释这件事
I can help you to explain this delicate matter to your aunt.
噢 真是太感谢你了
Oh,thank you so much.
玛丽? 是你吗? 事情怎么样了?
Mary? Is that you? How did it go?
波罗先生陪我一起来的 伊丽莎白姑妈
I 've got Mr.Poirot with me,Aunt Elizabeth.
我们一起坐巴士回的惠特科姆
We came back to Whitcomb on the bus together.
波罗先生是个有名的侦探
Mr.Poirot's a famous detective.
你以为我不知道吗?
Do you think I don't know that?
噢 你真是太客气了
Oh,you are too kind.
但是发生了很糟糕的事情 伊丽莎白姑妈
But something terrible's happened,Aunt Elizabeth.
我真的不知道该怎么告诉你
I don't really know how to tell you.
我很遗憾的告诉你 你的袖珍画像...
I regret to inform you that your miniatures...
被偷了
they ha ve been stolen.
被偷了?
Stolen?
但是 怎么会被偷呢?
But how could they be stolen?
它们是从哪被偷走的?
Where were they stolen from?
是我们停车在莱德伯恩吃午餐时
They were stolen from the bus
从巴士上被偷的
when we stopped for lunch at Redburn.
但是别担心
But ha ve no fear,
很快就会抓到歹徒的
it will not be long before the miscreants are apprehended.
别把我们交给我父亲 好吗?
Don't give us away to my father,will you?
噢 不 当然不会
Oh no,of course not.
你们打算去哪?
Where abouts are you headed?
不能告诉你
Can't tell you.
高兴点 黑斯廷斯上校
Cheer up,Captain Hastings.
噢 是啊
Oh,yes.
我肯定你会抓到小偷的
I 'm sure you'll catch your robber.
是啊 嗯
Yes,well,
我们唯一的嫌疑人走了
with our one and only suspect gone,
我要是知道怎么抓到他就好了
I 'm damned if I know how we're going to catch him.
嗯 黑斯廷斯上校?
Eh,Captain Hastings?
先给我来一份鱼汤 然后来一份黑线鳕
I think I 'll start with the fish soup,followed by the haddock.
我想试着刺激一下灰色小细胞
Try and shake up the old grey cells a bit.
我不懂的是
You see,what I can't understand is,
如果诺顿・凯恩不是那个留胡子的女人
if Norton Kane wasn't the woman with the moustache,
那谁是?
who was?
你已经做得很好了 黑斯廷斯
You have done your best,Hastings.
著名的贾普总探长
The renowned Chief Inspector Japp
肯定早就放弃了
would have given up long ago.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不会是嫉妒了吧 波罗?
You're not jealous,Poirot,are you?
贾普受邀去做演讲的事?
Japp being asked to give these lectures?
嫉妒?
Jealous?
我的天!
Nom de Dieu... !
这有什么让波罗感兴趣的呢?
Of what interest is it to Poirot,
惠特科姆妇女组织 嗯?
the Whitcombe Institution for Women,eh?
如果是皇家学会 现在...! 呃!
If it was the Royal Society,now... ! Eh !
但我完全不认为
But then I hardly think
贾普总探长会受到皇家学会的邀请
the Chief Inspector Japp would be invited by the Royal Society.
不不不
No,no,no.
只不过是惠特科姆妇女组织
It is only the Institution for Women at Whitcombe
他们会在这样的地方听到贾普总探长
and such places that they will listen to the Chief Inspector Japp
把赫尔克里・波罗破的案子说成他破的
claiming the cases of Hercule Poirot for his own.
噢 我肯定贾普不会这么做的!
Oh,I 'm sure Japp wouldn't do that!
黑斯廷斯 我们能说点别的吗?
Hastings,can we please talk of something else.
我对著名的贾普总探长没有兴趣
The renowned Chief Inspector is of no interest.
不 谢谢
No,thank you.
我明天要去见玛丽・杜兰特
I 've got to see Mary Durrant tomorow.
也许你应该让杜兰特小姐
Perhaps you should bring Mademoiselle Durrant
她的姑妈还有贝克・伍德先生见个面
and her aunt and Monsieur J.Baker Wood face to face
讨论一下此事
and discuss this thing.
噢 我看不出这能有什么用处
Oh,I don't see what good that'll do.
我不知道要对她和她姑妈说什么
I don't know what I 'm going to say to her and her aunt anyway.
你需要的是睡眠 黑斯廷斯
Sleep is the thing,Hastings.
我打算晚餐之后马上上床睡觉
For myself,I fully intend to get to bed immediately after dinner.
我强烈建议你也这么做
And I strongly advise you to do the same.
准备好点餐了吗 先生?
Ready to order,sir?
能借个火吗?
Do you have a light?
- 晚上好 先生 - 晚上好 警官
- Good evening,sir. - Good evening,constable.
别让你的女儿上台表演 沃辛顿太太
Don't put your daughter on the stage,Mrs.Worthington.
诺埃尔・柯沃德演唱的一首好歌
A fine song by Mr.Noel Coward
同样也对警察适用
and the same holds true for the Police Force.
请原谅
Pardon.
因为侦查是一项孤独的工作
...because detection is a darned lonely business
而侦探也许很可能变成孤狼
and detecives are perhaps inclined to be lone wolves,
如果你们不介意我这么说的话
if you'll pardon the expresion.
在一个案件结案时
And,at the conclusion of a case,
总会有其他人员 不是警察机关
there are always other parties,not of the Police Force,
声称是他们破的案
who will claim to have solved it.
我指的当然是警察生涯中的害虫
I refer of course to that bane of the policeman's life,
那些业余的侦探
the amateur sleuth.
或者更糟 专业的私家侦探
Or,worse still,the professional private detective.
女士们先生们 专业的私家侦探
The professional private detective,ladies and gentlemen,
并不是小说中的光辉人物
is not the glamorous figure of fiction.
他是个在更加有价值的行业里失败的人
He is a man who,failing in more worthy walks of life,
好管闲事 喜欢惹麻烦
and being of meddlesome and trouble making disposition,
最终在小吃店上面一间昏暗的办公室里落户
finally comes to rest in a dingy office over the chip shop,
他在那里调查小案件和离婚
where he plies for hire in the sordid world of petty crime and divorce.
但是我必须说 有一个人除外
Except,I have to say,for one.
我很有幸在我的职业生涯中 有很多
I ha ve been fortunate in my career in that many,
也许是大多数案件 都是和那位
indeed,perhaps most,of my cases ha ve been shared
最伟大的私家侦探一起完成的
with that most extraordinary of private detectives,
我要从他的母语中借用一个词
and if I may borrow a word from his own native tongue,
比利时警察机关的"老前辈"
that doyen of the Belgian Police Force,
赫尔克里・波罗先生
Monsieur Hercule Poirot.
我敢说
I think I may say without fear of contradiction
赫尔克里・波罗有着二十世纪
the Hercule Poirot has one of the most original minds
最有创意的想法
of the twentieth century.
聪明 勇敢
Intelligent,bra ve,
敏感 速度特别快
sensitive,devastatingly quick,
赫尔克里・波罗远远超过了
Hercule Poirot stands head and shoulders above
我丰富经验中的其他侦探
any other detective of my considerable experience.
莱蒙小姐 我真的很担心钥匙的事
I say,Miss Lemon,I 'm fearfully worried about the keys.
条理和方法 莱蒙小姐 条理和方法
Order and method,Miss Lemon. Order and method.
拉贡达里面有一个洞 莱蒙小姐
The Lagonda's got a hole in it,Miss Lemon,
你火烧屁股了 钥匙出问题了
the filly's on fire and the keys are bent.
你大难临头了 我们要幸灾乐祸了
Cent tonneres. Deux garcons sure le feu de joie.
灰色小细胞 莱蒙小姐
The little grey cells,Miss Lemon.
重建一下犯案的场景 朋友
Reconstruct the scene of the crime,mon ami.
来到门口
Come up to door.
从包里拿出钥匙
Take keys out of bag.
开门
Unlock door.
我进来了 迪克跟着我 还在说话
I come in. Dicker follows,still talking.
不应该鼓励他们 浪费你所有的钱...
Shouldn 't encourage 'em. Wastin 'all your money...
噢 起作用了
Oh,it works.
真的起作用了
It really works.
过来 黑斯廷斯
Come now,Hastings,
告诉我案件进展如何了
tell me where you stand in this case
我会尽最大努力帮你的
and Poirot will do his humble best to assist.
不 没用 案件没有任何进展
No,it's no good. I don't stand anywhere with the case really.
不管怎样 要面对问题的是我
Anyway,I 'm the one who's got to face the music.
嗯
Well.
- 黑斯廷斯上校 - 你好 杜兰特小姐
- Captain Hastings! - Hello,Miss Durrant.
你有消息了吗?
Have you got some news?
嗯 不 ...没有
Well,no... not really.
不 我理解
No,I understand.
你好 波罗先生
Hello,Monsieur Poirot.
小姐
Mademoiselle.
我还没有放弃
I ha ven't given up yet.
你姑妈的店铺真漂亮 小姐
You know,the shop of your aunt is beautiful,mademoiselle.
噢 你要是有时间 她会很高兴见到你的
Oh,she'd love to see you if you can spare a moment.
这是我们的荣幸
We would be delighted.
波罗先生来了 伊丽莎白姑妈
Monsieur Poirot's here,Aunt Elizabeth.
还有黑斯廷斯上校
And Captain Hastings.
噢 太好了!
Oh. How nice !
你成功帮我们找回袖珍画像了吗 波罗先生?
Have you managed to retrieve our miniatures for us,Monsieur Poirot?
啊 请原谅 女士
Ah,pardon,mademoiselle,
这件事是黑斯廷斯上校负责的
it is Captain Hastings who is in charge of this a ffair.
恐怕还没有
And he hasn't,I 'm afraid.
我们找到它们了 但不能拿回来
Well,we found them,all right,but we can't retrieve them.
伍德先生说他是真心买下它们的
Mr.Wood says he bought them in good faith,
所以东西是他的
so they're his.
这么说东西还在他手上?
So he's still got them?
不 已经被警察拿走了
No,the police ha ve taken them.
我会在适当的时机拿回它们的
But I 'll get them back in due course.
这要看法庭怎么决定
That depends on what the court decides.
如果我们能抓到小偷就有帮助了
It would help if we could catch the thief.
噢 我的天啊
Oh,my God.
怎么了 黑斯廷斯上校?
What is it,Captain Hastings?
我知道了! 我知道了!
I 've got it ! I 've got it!
我知道了! 佩恩小姐
I 've got it ! Miss Penn,
我能把你的袖珍画像拿回来!
I can get your miniatures back !
你也许也能帮上忙
You may be able to help,too.
失陪了
Excuse me.
黑斯廷斯! 等一下!
Hastings! Wait!
快点 波罗!
Come on,Poirot!
你到底在搞什么 黑斯廷斯?
What on earth are you playing at,Hastings?
我知道了 波罗!
I 've got it,Poirot !
什么? 你知道什么了?
What? What ha ve you got?
这个案子的答案! 肯定是黑线鳕的功劳
The answer to this case ! It must ha ve been the haddock.
我觉得棒极了!
I feel wonderful !
黑斯廷斯...!
Hastings... !
我稍后去酒店见你
I 'll see you at the hotel later.
我一说出来我就知道了
As soon as I said it I knew.
谁知道杜兰特小姐带着袖珍画像在路上了?
Who knew Miss Durrant was on her way with the miniatures?
谁知道她会在午餐时间停在雷德伯恩?
Who could have found out she'd be stopping at Redburn at lunch time
谁有快车能载他去温德米尔?
and who had a fast car to get him to Windermere?
我不知道 谁?
I don't know. Who?
当然是贝克・伍德他自己!
J.Baker Wood himself,of course !
真的吗?
Really?
我不相信有任何女人去见他了
I don't believe any woman ever came to see him.
我认为他去了莱德伯恩 自己偷了袖珍画像
I think he went to Redburn and stole the miniatures himself.
那船夫呢?
What about the ferryman?
他说的是他在车站载了一个女人
Well,all he said was he picked up a woman at the station
然后带载去了湖边酒店
and taken her to the Lake Hotel.
我想他一天要载很多女人去湖边酒店
I imagine he takes a dozen women a day to the Lake Hotel.
好吧 但我不知道你要做什么
All right. But I don't know what you're going to do.
嗯 这真的很简单
Well,it's quite simple,really.
伍德从没见过佩恩太太或杜兰特小姐
You see,Wood has never met Miss Penn or Miss Durrant.
我已经请他从温德米尔过来一趟了
I 've asked him to come over from Windermere.
当他看到这位漂亮的年轻小姐
Now when he sees this beautiful young girl
和她坐在轮椅上的姑妈
and her aunt in a wheelchair...
怎么?
What?
我敢说他会觉得相当愧疚
He's going to feel pretty damned small,I can tell you.
- 是吗? - 噢 是的
- Really? - Oh,yes.
即使是像他那样的狠心罪犯
I mean,even a hardened criminal like him
也不是完全没有心的 贾普
isn't entirely without a heart,Japp.
走吧
Come on.
请跟我来
If you'd like to follow me,
桌边有一个两人座的桌子
there's a table for two over by the window.
- 很好 - 谢谢
- Lovely. - Thank you.
希望他们不会迟到 时间非常的重要
I hope they're not going to be late. The timing's absolutely crucial.
既然你不告诉我是怎么回事 黑斯廷斯
Since I am not going to be told what is going on in this case of yours,Hastings,
我没办法和你讨论
I can make no intelligent contribution to any discussion of it.
是你说你不想和这案子扯上关系的!
Well,it was your idea you didn't want anything to do with it!
把这三个人聚到一起也是我的主意
It was my idea also to bring together these three people,
伍德先生 杜兰特小姐和佩恩太太
Monsieur Wood,Mademoiselle Durrant and Mademoiselle Penn.
- 我怎么不记得 - 好了 好了
- I don't remember that. - Now,now.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you are. - Thanks.
我们应该再点一盘三明治
We could have another plate of them sandwiches.
你应该吃慢点的
You should have made them last.
我以为茶晚一点才会上
I thought the proper tea was coming later.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
好了 稳一点 稳一点
All right,steady. Steady now.
开始了 警官
Here we go,Sarge.
- 什么? - 她们到了
- What? - They've arrived.
就像他说的 坐在轮椅上的年长女人
The old one in a wheelchair,like he said.
我应该坐你那边的
I should be sitting there.
坐在这里没有任何好处 我什么都看不到
It's no good me sitting here,I can't see nothing.
你能来真是太好了 佩恩太太
How good of you to come,Miss Penn.
请坐 杜兰特小姐
Do sit down,Miss Durrant.
这房间真漂亮!
What a handsome room !
这是伦敦警察厅的贾普总探长
This is Chief Inspector Japp of Scotland Yard.
真让人兴奋!
How exciting !
你好
How do you do?
你何不坐在波罗先生身边呢 佩恩太太?
Why don't you sit next to Monsieur Poirot,Miss Penn?
啊 女士
Ah. Mademoiselle.
伊丽莎白姑妈真的很希望你们带来了好消息
Aunt Elizabeth was so hoping you'd ha ve good news for us.
我也希望如此
Well,I hope so,too.
就这样吗? 只是希望?
Is that all? Just hope?
没事的 亲爱的玛丽
It's all right,Mary dear.
这亲爱的孩子 对我总是这么有保护欲
The dear child,she's so protective on my behalf.
佩恩太太 我能给你拿点吃的或咖啡吗?
Mademoiselle Penn,may I offer you something to eat or a cup of tea?
给我一杯茶吧
I 'd love a cup of tea.
现在怎么样了?
What's happening now?
没什么 就是闲聊
Nothing. Just gabbing.
坐在轮椅里学会的就是耐心 波罗先生
One learns patience sitting in a wheelchair,Monsieur Poirot.
我肯定这是真的 女士
I am sure that is true,mademoiselle.
上校站起来了
The Captain's standing up.
噢 是那个美国人 他来了
Oh,it's the Yank. He's arrived.
你能来真是太好了
It's very good of you to come.
你拿到袖珍画像了吗?
Do you have the miniatures?
就等时机成熟了
All in good time.
你说我能拿回它们的
You said I 'd get them back.
那是黑斯廷斯上校的客人
It is the guest of Captain Hastings.
如果我一路开车过来却一无所获...
If I 've driven all this way on a wild goose chase...
我能向你保证 只要你耐心等一下
I can assure you. If you'll just bear with me.
我觉得这家酒店会毁坏海岸线
I thought this hotel was going to spoil the coastline.
但在特定的时候 透过迷雾或在日落时
But at certain times,seen through the mist,or at sunset,
- 真的看起来... - 啊 佩恩太太
- it really looks... - Ah,Mademoiselle Penn,
我想迷雾已经开始散开了
the mist is beginning to clear,I think.
我想你没见过杜兰特小姐吧?
I don't think you've met Miss Durrant?
你好
How do you do?
我觉得不太舒服 玛丽
I feel unwell,Mary.
还有佩恩太太
And Miss Penn.
听着 这真是太客气了 但我没有...
Look,this is all very nice,but I didn't...
不 我没见过伍德先生 我们只是...
No,I 've never met Mr.Wood. We've only...
伍德先生?
Mr.Wood?
走吧 玛丽
Come along,Mary.
我姑妈不太舒服
My aunt isn't feeling well.
等一下! 等一下!
Hold on ! Hold on!
佩恩太太!
Mademoiselle Penn !
你怎么知道这就是伍德先生
How did you know it was Monsieur Wood,
佩恩太太?
Mademoiselle Penn?
没人提过他的名字
Nobody has mentioned his name.
不 我不知道 我只是...
Well,I didn't. I just...
你不可能认识他
You could not possibly ha ve known him.
除非你就是把袖珍画像卖给他
Not unless it was you who took the fifteen hundred pounds
得了一千五百英镑的人
from him for the miniatures.
嗯 就是她!
Why,it was her !
乔装成一个邋遢的女人
Made up to look like a frump,
但就是她!
but it was her !
让别人都以为是一个男人
Made up to make everybody else think that it was a man
乔装成女人 不是吗 佩恩太太?
dressed as a woman,n'est ce pas,Mademoiselle Penn?
你以为你可以得到那些钱
You thought that you would keep the money
同时拿回作为赃物的袖珍画像
and get back the miniatures as stolen property.
等一下 她...
Wait a minute. She...
干得不错 如果你能成功的话
Nice work,if you can get it.
那么 佩恩太太
So,Miss Penn,
你对这一切有什么话说?
what do you say to all this?
- 她跑了 警官 - 拦住她!
- She's off,Sarge. - Stop her !
好了 抓住你了
All right. Got you.
把她带走 警官
Take her away,Sergeant.
现在 小姐你呢?
And now,mademoiselle...?
你...!
You... !
- 还有她 - 别跑这么快啊 小姐
- And her. - Not so fast,miss.
把她们都关起来
Lock them both up.
但她...我不...
But she... I didn't...
我...
I...
黑斯廷斯一开始没看出来
Hastings couldn't see it at first.
他一直想找出袖珍画像是怎么
He was trying to work out how the miniatures
从莱德伯恩到温德米尔的
got from Redburn to Windermere.
正是
Quite. Exactly.
然后他意识到它们从未到过莱德伯恩
Then he realised they'd never even been in Redburn.
很不错 黑斯廷斯! 你判断出了犯罪的本质
Masterly,Hastings! You diagnosed the true nature of the crime.
噢 嗯...
Oh,well...
但是很不幸 你的陷阱找错了对象
Unfortunate,of course,that you set your trap for quite the wrong culprit.
打扰了
Excuse me.
谢谢
Merci.
打扰了 先生
Excuse me,sir,
您忘了您的收据
you forgot your receipt.
啊 非常感谢
Ah,merci beaucoup.
希望你住得愉快
I hope you enjoyed your stay.
是的
Yes,indeed.
先生们
Gentlemen.
- 啊 - 我来吧 波罗
- Ah. - Allow me,Poirot.
这上面有你呢 贾普
There's something about you here,Japp.
贾普总探长在北方城市的演讲旅行
''Chief Inspector Japp to speak in North Country Lecture Tour.''
你知道!
You knew !
这就是你把我一路拖过来的原因
That's why you dragged me all the way up here.
不不 我感兴趣的是背面的东西
No,no. It was the other side I was interested in.
我不知道...
I did not know that...
学会像法国人那样说法语?
''Learn to Speak French like a Frenchman?''
在比利时 黑斯廷斯
In Belgium,Hastings,
看别人的剪报
it is considered quite bad form
是很不礼貌的
to read another person's newspaper cuttings.
谢谢
Thank you.